Finding Aid for the Harold Monro Papers LSC.0745
UCLA Library Special Collections
Harold Monro papers
circa 1910-1935
UCLA Library Special Collections
Monro, Harold
LSC.0745
4.0 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Harold Edward Monro (1879-1932) founded Samurai Press, founded and edited the Poetry Review (1912), Poetry and Drama (1913-14) and the Monthly Chapbook (1919), and founded the Poetry Bookshop (1913). Although he is better known as an editor than a poet, he wrote and published poetry as well. The collection contains correspondence relating to the Poetry Bookshop and literary circles in London with which Harold Monro was associated as well as manuscripts by Monro and a few manuscripts of other authors.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
G.F. Sims, purchase, 1961.
Beryl Sims, purchase, 1961.
Alida Monro, purchase, 1961.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9924702573606533
Biography
Harold Edward Monro was born on March 14, 1879, St. Gilles, Belgium; educated at Radley, 1892-96, and Cambridge, 1898-1901; married Dorothy Elizabeth Browne, 1903; founded Samurai Press and published first book, Proposals for a Voluntary Nobility (1907); moved to London, 1911; founded and edited the Poetry Review, 1912; founded the Poetry Bookshop, 1913, where he met Alida Klementaski, who later became his second wife after his first marriage was dissolved in 1916; began poetry readings at Poetry Bookshop which continued up through the time of Monro's death; founded and edited Poetry and Drama (1913-14) and the Monthly Chapbook (1919); although better known as an editor than a poet, he continued to write and publish poetry, and The Collected Poems of Harold Monro was published in 1933; died after an extended illness, 1932.
Scope and Content
Collection contains correspondence relating to the Poetry Bookshop and literary circles in London with which Harold Monro was associated. Correspondents include T.S. Eliot, E.M. Forester, John Galsworthy, A.E. Houseman, D.H. Lawrence, Virginia Woolf, William Butler Yeats, and Ezra Pound. Collection also includes manuscripts by Monro as well as a few manuscripts of other authors. Contains a poem in French by Filippo Tommaso Marinetti titled, Bombardement d'Andrinople.
Expanded Scope and Content Note
This is a collection of correspondence, manuscripts, and ephemera of Harold Monro, London author, editor, publisher and bookseller. The correspondence, ca. 1910-1935, is addressed variously to Harold Monro or to his wife, Alida Klamantaski, and pertains to matters touching the Poetry Bookshop, poetry readings there, contributions to the periodicals published by Monro, as well as serious literary criticism, and aesthetics.
Monro's activities during those early years of the 20th Century were devoted to the support of modern literary movements, and the list of correspondents includes such recognized names as Walter De La Mare, Thomas Stearns Eliot, Edward Morgan Forster, John Galsworthy, Gordon Craig, Alfred Edward Housman, D.H. Iawrence, Amy Lowell, Wyndham Lewis, John Masefield, Alfred Noyes, Edith and Sacheverell Sitwell, Alec Waugh, Virginia Woolf, and William Butler Yeats, and Ezra Pound.
The correspondence ranges alphabetically through the first three boxes, and totals ca. 1500 items.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence (Boxes 1-3).
Manuscripts (Boxes 4-8).
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Harold Monro Papers (1 item).
Authors, English -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Poets, English -- 20th century -- Archives.; Marinetti, F.T.; Monro, Harold -- Archives; Poetry Bookshop
- Abercrombie, Lascelles, 1881-1938., (1 folder) 12 items. (Box 1)
- Acton, Harold Mario Mitchell, 1904-., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Aiken, Conrad Potter, 1889-., 5 items. (Box 1)
- Ainslie, Douglas, 1865-1948., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Aldington, Mrs. Hilda Doolittle, 1886-., 8 items. (Box 1)
  General note
  6 letters from H.D.; 2 letters to H.D.
- Aldington, Richard, 1892-., (4 folders) 134 items. (Box 1)
- Alford, Edward John Gregory, 1890-., (1 folder) 18 items. (Box 1)
- Anderson, John Redwood, 1883-., 6 items. (Box 1)
- Anrep, Boris., (1 folder) 15 items. (Box 1)
- Archer, William, 1856-1924., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Armstrong, Martin Donisthorpe, 1882-., 4 items. (Box 1)
- Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Bard, Josef., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Barnett, Harry Villiers, 1858-1928., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Barry, Iris, 1895-., 6 items. (Box 1)
- Batterham, Eric N., 1898-1936., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Bax, Clifford, 1886-., (1 folder) 34 items. (Box 1)
- Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Benson, Arthur Christopher, 1862-1925., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Birch, Frank, 1889-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Bithell, Jethro, 1878-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Bosanquet, Theodora, B., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Bosschére, Jean de, 1878-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Bottomley, Gordon, 1874-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Brown, Alec, 1900-., (1 folder) 16 items. (Box 1)
- Bruno, Guido, 1884-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Bullen, Arthur Henry, 1857-1920., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Bullett, Gerald William, 1894-., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Bynner, Witter, 1881-., 3 items; and 1 photograph of Bynner inscribed to Monro. (Box 1)
- Cammaerts, Émile., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Campbell, Archibald Young, 1885-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Campbell, Joseph, 1879-., 2 items. (Box 1)
  Also, 1 from his wife, Nancy Campbell.
- Carpenter, Edward, 1844-1929., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Carter, Huntley, d. 1942., 5 items. (Box 1)
- Chalmers, Patrick Reginald, 1872-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Chase, Lewis Nathaniel, 1873-1937., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Childe, Wilfrid Rowland, 1890-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Church, Richard, 1893-., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Clarke, Amy Key., 4 items. (Box 1)
- Cole, George Douglas Howard, 1889-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Cook, Harold Lewis., 5 items. (Box 1)
- Cook, Henry Caldwell, 1886-1939., 5 items. (Box 1)
- Coppard, Alfred Edgar, 1878-., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Cowdroy, Joan Agnes, d. 1946., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Craig, Edward Gordon, 1872-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Crow, Gerald H., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Cullis, Michael Fowler, 1914-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Cunnard, Nancy, 1896-1965., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Davidson, Edward., (1 folder) 16 items. (Box 1)
- Davies, Oliver., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Davies, William Henry, 1871-1940., 3 items. (Box 1)
- de Bary, Mrs. Anna., 2 items. (Box 1)
- De La Mare, Walter, 1873-., 6 items. (Box 1)
- Dent, Edward Joseph, 1876-., 10 items. (Box 1)
- Deutsch, Babette, 1895-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Dobreé, Bonamy, 1891-., (1 folder) 21 items. (Box 1)
- Dogdson, Campbell, 1867-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Douglas, Norman, 1868-1952., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Doyle, Camilla., (1 folder) 18 items. (Box 1)
- Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937., 6 items. (Box 1)
- Dukes, Ashley, 1885-., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Dunsany, Edward John Moreton Drax Plunkett, 18th baron, 1878-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Earle, Ferdinand., (1 folder) 10 items. (Box 1)
- Eden, Mrs. Helen (Parry) 1885-., 4 items. (Box 1)
- Eliot, Thomas Stearns, 1888-1965., (1 folder) 12 items. (Box 1)
- Ellis, Vivian Locke., 6 items. (Box 1)
- Elton, Godfrey Elton, baron, 1892-., 5 items. (Box 1)
- Epstein, Margaret Gilmour Dunlop (Mrs. Jacob Epstein) d. 1947., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Farjeon, Eleanor, 1881-., 6 items. (Box 1)
- Flecker, Hellé (Mrs. James Elfroy)., 4 items. (Box 1)
- Fletcher, John Gould, 1886-1951., (1 folder) 33 items. (Box 1)
- Flint, Frank Stewart, 1885-., (1 folder) 17 items. (Box 1)
- Ford, Madox Ford, 1873-1939. Also: Esther Ford., (1 folder) 23 items. (Box 1)
- Forster, Edward Morgan, 1879-., 1 item. (Box 1)
  Abinger (n.d.).
- Fox-Strangways, Arthur Henry, 1859-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Fraser, Claud Lovat, 1890-1921., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Fraser, Ronald, 1888-., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Freeman, John, 1880-1929., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Gale, Norman Rowland, 1862-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Gertler, Mark, 1892-1939., 2 items. (Box 1)
- Gibbons, Stella, 1902-., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Gibson, Wilfrid Wilson, 1878-., 4 items. (Box 1)
- Gill, Eric, 1882-1940., 4 items. (Box 1)
- Ginner, Charles, 1878-., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Gollancz, Sir Israel, 1864-1931., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Gosse, Sir Edmund William, 1849-1928., (1 folder) 17 items. (Box 1)
- Granville-Barker, Harley Granville, 1877-1946., 1 item. (Box 1)
- Graves, Alfred Perceval, 1846-1931., 3 items. (Box 1)
- Guthrie, James Joshua, 1874-., (1 folder) 10 items. (Box 1)
- Halliday, Frank Wade, 1876-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Hare, Kenneth, 1888-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Harris, Frank, 1855-1931., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Hart, Mabel., 4 items. (Box 2)
- Haward, Lawrence, 1878-., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Helston, John, 1877-., (1 folder) 15 items. (Box 2)
- Heinemann, William, 1863-1920., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Herbert, Alan Patrick, 1890-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Herron, George Davis, 1862-1925., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Heseltine, Philip, 1894-1930., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Hewlett, Maurice Henry, 1861-1923., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Hinkson, Mrs. Katherine (Tynan) 1861-1931., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Hodgson, Ralph., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Holley, Horace, 1887-., 1 item (Box 2)
- Housman, Alfred Edward, 1859-1936., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Hughes, Richard Arthur Warren, 1900-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Hussey, Dyneley, 1893-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Gooden, Stephen, 1892-1955., 1 item. (Box 2)
  Letter to H.M., February 9, 1930. This letter is addressed to Dear Munro. Ex libris: W.O. Schneider, who describes it in his list of prints as a letter to H. Munro.
- Ingram, Kenneth, 1882-., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Jackson, Holbrook, 1874-1948., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Johnston, Edward, 1872-. Also: Gunnar Johnston., (1 folder) 12 items. (Box 2)
- Jones, David Michael, 1895-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Kauffer, Edward McKnight, 1891-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Knox, Edmund George Valpy, 1881-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-., (1 folder) 28 items. (Box 2)
- Langdon-Davies, John, 1897-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Lawrence, David Herbert, 1885-1930., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Le Gallienne, Richard, 1866-1947., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Leslie, Shane, 1885-., 7 items. (Box 2)
- Levine, Isaac Don, 1892-., (1 folder) 16 items. (Box 2)
- Lewis, Wyndham, 1886-1957., (1 folder) 28 items. (Box 2)
  24 from W.L.; 4 H.M. carbons.
- Lindsay, Jack, 1900-., 4 items. (Box 2)
- Lowell, Amy, 1874-1925., (1 folder) 10 items. (Box 2)
- Lysaght, Sydney Royse, d. 1941., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Macaulay, Rose., 5 items. (Box 2)
- MacDonagh, Thomas, 1878-1915., 2 items. (Box 2)
- MacDougall, Allan Ross, 1893-., 9 items. (Box 2)
- Macfall, Haldane, 1860-1928., 2 items. (Box 2)
- MacGill, Patrick, 1890-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Malleson, Miles, 1888-., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Mallock, William Hurrell, 1849-1923., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Manning, Frederic., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Marinetti, Filippo Tommaso, 1876-., (1 folder) 15 items. (Box 2)
- Masefield, Mrs. Constance (Mrs. John Masefield)., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Masefield, John, 1878-., 5 items. (Box 2)
- Maynard, Theodore, 1890-1956., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Methuen, Sir Algernon Methuen Marshall, bart., 1856-1924., (1 folder) 27 items. (Box 2)
- Mew, Charlotte Mary, 1870-1928., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Meynell, Francis, 1891-., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Meynell, Viola., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Milton, Ernest, 1892-., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Moncreiff, Frederick Charles, 1847-1929., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Monkhouse, Allan, 1887-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Monroe, Harriet, 1860-1936., 4 items. (Box 2)
- Moore, Marianne, 1887-., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Moore, Thomas Sturge, 1870-., (1 folder) 50 items. (Box 2)
- Nash, Paul, 1889-1946., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Nevinson, Christopher Richard Wynne, 1889-., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Newbolt, Sir Henry John, 1862-1928., (1 folder) 38 items. (Box 2)
- Michols, Robert Malise Bowyer, 1893-., 12 items. (Box 2)
- Nicolson, Hon. Harold George, 1886., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Noyes, Alfred, 1880-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- O'Brien, Edward Joseph Harrington, 1890-1941., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Odgen, Charles Kay, 1889-1957., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Osborn, Edward Bolland, 1867-., 4 items. (Box 2)
- Ould, Hermon, 1886-., 5 items. (Box 2)
- Palmer, Herbert Edward, 1880-., (1 folder) 18 items. (Box 2)
- Pearce, C Maresco, 1874-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Pepler, Hilary Douglas C., 6 items. (Box 2)
- Phillpotts, Eden, 1862-., 6 items. (Box 2)
- Plarr, Victor Gustave, 1863-1929., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Playfair, Sir Nigel Ross, 1874-1934., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Plowman, Max, 1883-., 3 items. (Box 2)
- Poel, William, 1852-1934., 2 items. (Box 2)
- Poortenaar, Jan, 1886-., 5 items. (Box 2)
- Pound, Ezra Loomis, 1885-., (1 folder) 69 items. (Box 2)
- Pryce, Richard, 1864-., 1 item. (Box 2)
- Quennell, Peter, 1905-., 4 items. (Box 2)
- Randall, Sir Alec Walter George, 1892-., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Rawlence, Guy, 1888-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Read, Herbert Edward, 1893-., (1 folder) 9 items. (Box 3)
- Rhodes, Raymond Crompton., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Rhys, Ernes, 1859-., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Richard, Grant, 1872-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Richardson, Anthony, 1899-., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Roberts, Mrs. Mary (Fanton) 1871-., 5 items. (Box 3)
- Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935., 5 items. (Box 3)
- Rodker, John, 1894-., (1 folder) 25 items. (Box 3)
- Ross, Robert Baldwin, 1869-1918., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Ross, Sir Ronald, 1857-1932., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Rothenstein, Sir William, 1872-., 6 items. (Box 3)
- Royde-Smith, Naomi Gwladys., 11 items. (Box 3)
- Russell, George William, 1867-1935., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Rutherston, Albert Daniel, 1881-., 7 items. (Box 3)
- Rutland, Violet, duchess of, d. 1937., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Sabin, Arthur Knowles, 1879-., (1 folder) 17 items. (Box 3)
- Sackville, Lady Margaret, 1881-., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Sargant, Ethel, 1863-1918., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Sarojin Nyadu, 1879-., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Sassoon, Siegried, 1886-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Scott, Dixon, 1881-1915., (1 folder) 13 items. (Box 3)
- Scott, Harold., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Shanks, Edward, 1892-., (1 folder) 25 items. (Box 3)
- Seaman, Sir Owen, 1861-1936., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Shaw, George Bernard, 1856-1950., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Shove, Mrs. Fredegond., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Sinclair, May, d. 1946., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Sitwell, Edith, 1887-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1897-., 5 items. (Box 3)
- Smith, Logan Pearsall, 1865-1946., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Spare, Austin Osman., 4 items. (Box 3)
- Spencer, Stanley, 1891-., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Squire, John Collings, 1884-., 8 items. (Box 3)
- Stephens, James, 1882-1950., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Strong, Leonard Alfred George, 1896-1958., (1 folder) 20 items. (Box 3)
- Swingler, Randall., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Tagore, Rabindeanath, 1861-1941., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Talbot, Ethel., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Thomas, Edward, 1878-1917., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Thorly, Wilfrid Charles, 1878-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Thorold, Algar Labouchére, 1866-1936., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Torrence, Frederic Ridgely, 1875-., 4 items. (Box 3)
- Trench, Herbert, 1865-1923., (1 folder) 15 items. (Box 3)
- Turner, Walter James, 1889-., 5 items. (Box 3)
- Underwood, Leon, 1890-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-., (1 folder) 18 items. (Box 3)
- Upward, Allen, 1863-1926., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Verhaeren, Émile, 1855-1916., 6 items. (Box 3)
- Vildrac, Charles, 1882-., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Vinal, Harold, 1891-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Vines, Sherard, 1890-., 6 items. (Box 3)
- Wadsworth, Edward Alexander, d. 1949., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Waley, Arthur David, 1889-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Watts-Dunton, Walter Theodore, 1832-1914., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Waugh, Alec, 1898-., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Waugh, Arthur, 1866-1943., 2 items. (Box 3)
- Webster, Mary Morison., (1 folder) 15 items. (Box 3)
- Wells, Geoffrey Harry, 1900-., 3 items. (Box 3)
  Wells, H.G. see (Box 6, folder R).
- White, Ethelbert., 5 items. (Box 3)
- White, Mrs. Betty., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Whitworth, Geoffrey Arundel, 1854-., (1 folder) 14 items. (Box 3)
- Wickham, Mrs. Anna (Hepburn)., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Williams, Alfred, 1885(?)-1930., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Williams, Geoffrey Sydney, 1871-., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Williams, Iolo Aneurin, 1890-., 3 items. (Box 3)
- Williams-Ellis, Mrs. Amabel, 1894-., (1 folder) 10 items. (Box 3)
- Wolfe, Humbert, 1885-1940., 9 items. (Box 3)
- Woods, Margaret Louisa (Bradley) 1856-1945., (1 folder) 13 items. (Box 3)
- Woolf, Virginia, (Stephen) 1882-1941., 4 items. (Box 3)
- Yeats, Jack Butler, 1871-., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Yeats, William Butler, 1865-1939., 1 item. (Box 3)
- Correspondence--Unidentified., 13 items. (Box 3)
  Contains an unaddressed from letter, unsigned, from Mrs. Monro, June 22, 1935, giving notice of the closing down of the Poetry Bookshop.
- Ephemera--Press cuttings, brochures, leaflets regarding Monro's correspondents., 15 items. (Box 3)
  Contains: Letters to my Father-in-Law, no.1 by Lord Alfred Douglas. 19 Royal Avenue, Sloane Square, S.W., March 20, 1914. Typeset.
- Miscellaneous Manuscripts Sent to Monro By His Correspondents, (23 items)
  - Begbie, Harold, 1871-1929. The Builder. Cornwall., n.d.; Holograph. 3 leaves. (Box 3)
  - Coats, Victoria, Electric Light. n.p., n.d.; Holograph. 4 leaves. (Box 3)
  - Lindsay, Jack, 1900-. The Cheat, and A Mirror. n.p., Typescript. (Box 3)
  - Moncrieff, Frederick Charles, 1847-1929. Lines Wrote on the London and North Western Railway. Edinburgh, April 22, 1914., Holograph. (Box 3)
  - Pease, Maude Grace. A Outrance. London., Typescript. (Box 3)
  - Pepler, Hilary Douglas C. Three Pennyworth. n.p., n.d.; Holograph. 3 leaves. (Box 3)
  - Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1897-. Two Odes in Praise of Popular Music. n.p., n.d.; Holograph. 3 leaves. (Box 3)
  - Slessor, Kenneth. The Ghost. n.p., n.d.; Typescript. (Box 3)
  - Ould, Hermon, 1886-. My Spirit Walks Alone. n.p., n.d.; Holograph. (Box 3)
    Also in this folder: a manuscript of Harold Monro's, and 9 party lists, ca. 1925-1930.
- Boxes 4-8: Harold Monro's Manuscripts
  - Complete Manuscript of Evolution of the Soul. (Box 4, Folder A)
  - Complete Manuscript of Chronicle of a Pilgrimage. (Box 4, Folder B)
  - Goldoni Books., 4 items (143pp.). (Box 4, Folder C)
  - Poems written., 1918-19.; (139pp.). (Box 4, Folder D)
  - Poems written., 1921.; (126pp.). (Box 4, Folder D)
  - Poems written., 1922.; (71pp.). (Box 4, Folder E)
  - Poems written., 1923.; (72pp.). (Box 4, Folder E)
  - Poems written., 1929.; (21pp.). (Box 4, Folder F)
  - To A God I Once Knew., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder A)
    (Poetry & Notes).
  - Dream Exhibition of A Final World., (31pp.). (Box 5, Folder A)
  - Journey to Reclaim a Ghost., (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder A)
  - Manuscript., (26pp.). (Box 5, Folder A)
  - Labour Song., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder A)
  - Notes on The Use of Poetry., (30pp.). (Box 5, Folder A)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscript Fragments., (5pp.). (Box 5, Folder A)
  - Any Man's Daughter., (16pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
    Poetry & Notes.
  - Seed-Time Outside Eden., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Return., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - A Bomb Ballad., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Bitter Sanctuary., (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Solomon in the Forest., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Country Rhymes., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - A Man Still Alive., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Zeppelins Over London., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Barrel Organ Love., (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Sentry., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Notes on Elementary Instruction in the Use of Modern Contrivances., (3pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Change of House [becomes The Empty House]., (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Fateful Insomnia., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - The Staircase., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - The Hall., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Dreams., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - The Party., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Falling Leaves., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - Miscellaneous Fragments., (16pp.). (Box 5, Folder B)
  - The Understudy. Rough notes for projected play., (29pp.). (Box 5, Folder C)
  - The Silent Pool., Includes galley proofs (6pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Barrel Organ Love., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Change of Mind., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Strange Meeting. [fragment]., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Earthiness., Includes galley proofs (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - While We Sleep., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Unknown Country., Includes galley proofs (5pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Outside Eden., Includes galley proofs (5pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - This Our Life., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Winter Ocean., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Too Near the Sea., Autographed (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Street Fight., Autographed (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Natural History., Autographed (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Youth in Arms., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Annunciation. with corrections., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - The Pale Voice [becomes Fragments]. with corrections., Includes galley proofs (8pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Underworld., (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Fate., Includes galley proofs (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - The Garden., Includes galley proofs (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Spring., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Introspection., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Tell Me About That Harvest Field., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - From An Old House., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Dog., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Goldfish., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Thistledown., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - City-Storm., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Men Carrying Bale., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Blurred Etching., Autographed. Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - On the Destruction of the Foundling Hospital., Autographed. Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Love in the Autumn Forest., Autographed. Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Lovers in a London Shadow., (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Living., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - The Ocean in London., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - From Dark to Dark., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Where she Lives., Autographed. Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Holy Matrimony. With corrections., Includes galley proofs (3pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - The Earth for Sale., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Great Distance., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Romantic Fool Who Cannot Speak., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - One Moment Only., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Real Property., (3pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Gravity., Includes galley proofs (2pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - The Nightingale Near the House., Includes galley proofs (1p.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Living; From Dark to Dark; The Ocean in London. Galleys from poems published in The New Criterion., Includes galley proofs. (Box 5, Folder D)
  - Real Property. With corrections., Includes galley proofs (10pp.). (Box 5, Folder D)
  - The Circus. Projected play in four acts., Manuscript and typescript. (Box 5, Folder E)
  - The Great Joke., (6pp.). (Box 5, Folder F)
    Prose Essays & Lectures.
  - Thinking of People., (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder F)
  - Poetry of the Future., (3pp.). (Box 5, Folder F)
  - Unnecessary Books., (12pp.). (Box 5, Folder F)
  - The Sober Man. Dialogue for projected play., (15pp.). (Box 5, Folder G)
  - Miscellaneous prose notes., (4pp.). (Box 5, Folder G)
  - The Amphibians., Typescript (16pp.). (Box 5, Folder H)
    Short Stories.
  - Warlock., Typescript (38pp.). (Box 5, Folder H)
  - Paul Amouré., Typescript. Autographed (24pp.). (Box 5, Folder H)
  - Notes on poems of Roy Campbell., (5pp.). (Box 5, Folder I)
    Prose Notes.
  - Notes on meetings with D.H. Lawrence., (9pp.). (Box 5, Folder I)
  - Notes and news from England., (45pp.). (Box 5, Folder I)